Guide to the John E. Brennan Outdoor Advertising Survey Reports, 1947-1980 and undated RL.00148
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Outdoor Advertising Survey Reports, 1947-1980 (bulk 1947-1960s)
  - Reports Organized by City (alphabetical)
    - New Haven, Conn., #101, 1958 Dec. (Box 54)
    - New Orleans #1, 1963 Aug. (Box 54)
    - New Orleans #2, 1963 Dec. (Box 54)
    - New York #1, 1965 Apr. (Box 54)
    - New York #2, 1965 July (Box 54)
    - New York #3, 1965 Oct. (Box 54)
    - New York #3-C, 1965 Oct. (survey of children) (Box 54)
    - New York #4, 1965 Nov. (Box 54)
    - Omaha #1, 1963 May (Box 54)
    - Omaha #2, 1963 Nov. (Box 54)
    - Phoenix #1, 1963 July (Box 54)
    - Phoenix #2, 1963 Nov. (Box 54)
    - Pittsburgh #1, 1963 May (Box 55)
    - Pittsburgh #2, 1963 Aug. (Box 55)
    - Pittsburgh #3, 1963 Nov. (Box 55)
    - Pittsburgh #4, 1964 Feb. (Box 55)
    - Pueblo #1, 1965 Mar. (Box 55)
    - Richmond #1, 1963 June (Box 55)
    - Richmond #2, 1963 Dec. (Box 55)
    - Rochester #1, 1963 Sept. (Box 55)
    - Sacramento #1, 1964 Feb. (Box 55)
    - San Francisco #1, 1961 Jan. (Box 55)
    - San Francisco #2, 1961 Feb. (Box 55)
    - San Francisco #3, 1961 Mar. (Box 55)
    - San Francisco #4, 1961 Apr. (Box 55)
    - San Francisco #5, 1961 May (Box 55)
    - San Francisco #6, 1961 June (Box 56)
    - San Francisco #7, 1961 July (Box 56)
    - San Francisco #8, 1961 Aug. (Box 56)
    - San Francisco #9, 1961 Sept. (Box 56)
    - San Francisco #10, 1961 Oct. (Box 56)
    - San Francisco #11, 1961 Nov. (Box 56)
    - San Francisco #12, 1961 Dec. (Box 56)
    - San Francisco #13, 1962 Jan. (Box 56)
    - San Francisco #14, 1962 Feb. (Box 56)
    - San Francisco #15, 1962 Mar. (Box 56)
    - San Francisco #16, 1962 Apr. (Box 56)
    - San Francisco #17, 1962 May (Box 57)
    - San Francisco #18, 1962 June (Box 57)
    - San Francisco #19, 1962 July (Box 57)
    - San Francisco #20, 1962 Aug. (Box 57)
    - San Francisco #21, 1962 Sept. (Box 57)
    - San Francisco #22, 1962 Oct. (Box 57)
    - San Francisco #23, 1962 Nov. (Box 57)
    - San Francisco #24, 1962 Dec. (Box 57)
    - San Francisco #25, 1963 Jan. (Box 57)
    - San Francisco #26, 1963 Feb. (Box 57)
    - San Francisco #27, 1963 Mar. (Box 57)
    - San Francisco #28-1, 1963 Apr. (Box 57)
    - San Francisco #28-2, 1963 May 3 (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #28-3, 1963 May 10 (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #28-4, 1963 May 17 (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #28-5, 1963 May 24 (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #29, 1963 May 31 (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #30, 1963 July (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #31, 1963 Aug. (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #32, 1963 Sept. (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #33, 1963 Oct. (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #34, 1963 Nov. (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #35, 1963 Dec. (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #36, 1964 Jan. (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #37, 1964 Feb. (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #38, 1964 Mar. (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #39, 1964 Aug. (Box 58)
    - San Francisco #40, 1964 Nov. (Box 58)
    - San Jose #41 and #42, 1980 May, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Seattle #1, 1963 May (Box 59)
    - Seattle #2, 1963 July (Box 59)
    - Seattle #3, 1963 Sept. (Box 59)
    - Seattle #4, 1963 Nov. (Box 59)
    - Seattle #5, 1964 Jan. (Box 59)
    - St. Louis #1, 1963 May (Box 59)
    - St. Louis #2, 1963 Aug. (Box 59)
    - St. Louis #3, 1963 Nov. (Box 59)
    - Tulsa #1, 1963 July (Box 59)
    - Tulsa #2, 1964 Jan. (Box 59)
  - Reports Organized by Product Type
    - Beer Posters, 1963, 4 folders (Box 60)
    - Confection Posters, 1963 (Box 60)
    - Drug and Toiletry Posters, 1963, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Insurance and Utility Posters, 1963, 3 folders (Box 61)
    - Liquor Posters, Book 1, 1963, 4 folders (Box 61)
    - Liquor Posters, Book 2, 1963, 2 folders (Box 61)
    - Liquor Posters, Book 2, 1963, 2 folders (Box 62)
    - Liquor Posters, Book 3, 5 folders (Box 62)
    - Passenger Car and Truck Posters, Book 1, 1963, 2 folders (Box 62)
    - Passenger Car and Truck Posters, Book 1, 1963 (Box 63)
    - Passenger Car and Truck Posters, Book 2, 1963, 3 folders (Box 63)
    - Petroleum Posters, 1963, 3 folders (Box 63)
    - Petroleum Posters, 1963 (Box 64)
    - Soft Drink Posters, 1963, 4 folders (Box 64)
    - Tire-Battery and Accessory, 1963, 2 folders (Box 64)
    - Miscellaneous Posters, 1963, 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Loose Photographs, 1949-1959 and undated
    These color photographs were found loose within the collection. Since they are of the same size and content as survey report photos, it is presumed they were used in surveys, perhaps even belonging to some of the collection reports. Researchers who come across a survey report with missing photos may find them here.
    Photos were separated into product type categories, described at the end of this finding aid. These groups were often further subdivided, e.g. by brand name. For instance, most Ford cars are grouped together within the Automotive category. Most of the photos are undated but seem to center on the 1950s. Nearly all of the billboard advertisements in these photos contain illustrations, not photographic images, and the billboards have latticework around the structure bases. Besides billboards, several truck-side advertisements are also included. Products often pictured include cars and car products, soft drinks, beer, paper goods, cigarettes, bread, crackers, snack foods, and gasoline. Prominent brands featured are Pure, Gulf, Ford, Chevrolet, Nash, Schlitz, Budweiser, Mrs. Baird's, and Humble gasoline.
    - Amusement & Entertainment, Apparel, and Automotive, 1940s-1950s and undated (Box 65)
    - Beverages, undated (Box 65)
    - Business & Technology, undated (Box 65)
    - Consumer Goods & Services, undated (Box 65)
    - Food & Restaurants, undated (Box 65)
    - Public Service, undated (Box 65)
    - Retail, undated (Box 65)
    - Transportation & Travel, and Miscellaneous, undated (Box 65)
- Summary Data Files, 1947-1960s
  While the Summary Sheets listed below logically belong in this category, other information that was (1) summary in form and (2) related directly to Brennan's surveys was also placed in this series. The Summary Data Files do not contain summary data for all of the surveys represented in the previous series. However, most of the information grouped by city below is also represented on corresponding pages within the Outdoor Advertising Survey Reports Series.
  Some early reports do not indicate whether the data is from a masked remembrance or an unmasked remembrance survey. In cases where a folder holds one or more of these older reports, the folder is simply labeled Remembrance without the word masked or unmasked. Also included are lists of posters used in surveys for particular cities. Cities with at least one folder of information are listed individually below. Summary information for other cities may be found in folders labeled Various Cities. The series ends with miscellaneous summary information from the surveys, such as remembrance data listed by advertisement product type.
  Cities are listed below in alphabetical order. See also Legal Size Files.
  - Summary Information Organized by City (Box 65)
    - Cincinnati
      - Summary Sheets
        - Remembrance Scores, Surveys 1-119, 1948 June-1958 July (Box 65)
        - Unmasked Remembrance Scores, Surveys 11-119, 1949 July-1958 July (Box 65)
        - Correct ID Scores, Surveys 11-119, 1949 July-1958 July (Box 65)
      - Poster Listings, 1948-1958 (Box 65)
    - Dallas
      - Summary Sheets
        - Masked Remembrance Scores, Surveys 1-76, 1949 May-1955 Aug. (Box 65)
        - Unmasked Remembrance Scores, Surveys 17-76, 1950 Sept.-1955 Aug. (Box 66)
        - Correct ID Scores, Surveys 17-76, 1950 Sept.-1955 Aug. (Box 66)
      - Poster Listings, 1949-1955 (Box 66)
      - Miscellaneous, 1954-1955 (Box 66)
    - Fresno
      - Summary Sheets
        - Remembrance and Correct ID Scores, Surveys 1-4, undated (Box 66)
    - Houston
      - Summary Sheets
        - Remembrance Scores, Surveys 1-104, 1955 Sept.-1966 Sept. (Box 66)
        - Unmasked Remembrance Scores, Surveys 1-56, 1955 Sept.-1960 Apr. (Box 66)
        - Correct ID Scores, Surveys 1-56, 1955 Sept.-1960 Apr. (Box 66)
      - Poster Listings, 1955-1966 (Box 66)
    - Los Angeles
      - Summary Sheets
        - Masked Remembrance Scores, Surveys 2-170, 1949 May-1963 May (Box 66)
        - Unmasked Remembrance Scores, Surveys 1-133, 1949 Apr.-1960 Apr. (Box 66)
        - Unmasked Remembrance Scores, Surveys 171-209, 1963 June-1966 May (Box 66)
        - Correct ID Scores, Surveys 1-133, 1949 Apr.-1960 Apr. (Box 66)
      - Readership Scores by Posting Date, 1949 Apr.-1960 Jan., Typed with letter to Foster and Kleiser (Box 67)
      - Readership Scores by Posting Date, 1949 Apr.-1960 Jan., Handwritten (Box 67)
      - Poster Listings, 1955-1958 and undated (Box 67)
      - Poster Listings, 1958-1966 (Box 67)
    - New Haven
      - Summary Sheets
        - Remembrance Scores, Surveys 7-101, 1948 Apr.-1958 Dec. (Box 67)
        - Unmasked Remembrance Scores, Surveys 17-101, 1951 Dec.-1958 Dec. (Box 67)
        - Correct ID Scores, Surveys 17-101, 1951 Dec.-1958 Dec. (Box 67)
      - Poster Listings, 1947-1958 (Box 67)
    - San Francisco
      - Summary Sheets
        - Masked and Unmasked Remembrance Scores, Surveys 1-40, 1961 Jan.-1964 Nov. (Box 67)
      - Poster Listings, 1961-1964 (Box 67)
    - Various Cities (Akron-Indianapolis)
      - Summary Sheets
        - Unmasked Remembrance Scores, 1948 Dec.-1966 June (Box 67)
    - Various Cities (Jackson-Tulsa)
      - Summary Sheets
        - Unmasked Remembrance Scores, 1963 May-1965 Oct. (Box 67)
    - Poster Listings by city, 1949-1965 (incomplete) (Box 67)
  - Other Summary Information (Box 68)
    - Product Group Remembrance Scores, 1954-1955 (Box 68)
      (Remembrance scores for advertisements organized by product groups)
    - Classification Information, 1960s
      (Surveys [partial list?] are listed by product categories)
      - Agriculture & Chemicals through Drug & Toiletry (Box 68)
      - Food through Gas & Oil (Box 68)
      - Household & Wearing Apparel through Liquor (Box 68)
      - Miscellaneous through Passenger Cars & Trucks (Box 68)
      - Soft Drinks through Travel & Hotel (Box 68)
    - Design numbers, Master Record, 1947-1957 (Box 68)
    - Popularity of Outdoor Advertising in Six Markets, 1953 and undated (Box 68)
- Copy Clues, 1950-1957
  Copy Clues were monthly reports by Brennan that capitalized on the data compiled from surveys. Each folder appears to contain data and written information used in creating an individual Copy Clues issue, which was focused on one topic. Formats include adding machine tape, hand calculations on ledger paper, and typed, hand-edited drafts. The Copy Clues issue itself usually consists of one to several pages, with one or two color photos of example billboards, data and explanatory information. Finished copies can often be found in the final (comprehensive) folders if not earlier in the series.
  Brennan used survey data to draw conclusions on advertising design and passed this information on to subscribers. For instance, he used remembrance and identification scores to decide if advertisements showing two people scored better than advertisements with only one. Did a multicolor background score better than an advertisement with a solid color in the background? Such information was valuable to advertisers and advertising agencies in designing more effective advertisements.
  - Topic List (A List of Outdoor Survey Subjects Upon Which We Have Reported), 1950-1956 (Box 69)
  - #1, 1950 July, Designs Portraying Boys (Box 69)
  - #2, 1950 Aug., Illustrations of Men vs. Women (Box 69)
  - #3, 1950 Sept., One Person vs. Two or More (Box 69)
  - #4, 1950 Oct., Hand Designs (Box 69)
  - #5, 1950 Nov., Lettering Only (Box 69)
  - #6, 1951 Jan. [1950 Dec.?], Lettering Plus Illustration of Inanimate Object (Box 69)
  - #7, 1951 Jan., Lettering Plus Illustration of Package or Product (Box 69)
  - #8, 1951 Feb., Two-Person Designs (Box 69)
  - #9, 1951 Mar., Beer Posters with Appetite Appeal (Box 69)
  - #10, 1951 Apr., Food Product Posters with Appetite Appeal (Box 69)
  - #11, 1951 May, Appetite Appeal Posters With People vs. Without People (Box 69)
  - #12, 1951 June, Beer Posters With People vs. Without People (Box 69)
  - #13, 1951 July, Backgrounds: Colored vs. White (Box 69)
  - #14, 1951 Aug., Food Posters Using a Person and Appetite Appeal (Box 69)
  - #15, 1951 Sept., Santa Claus Posters (Box 69)
  - #16, 1951 Oct., Pictorial Background Posters (Box 69)
  - #17, 1951 Nov., Cartoon Posters (Box 69)
  - #18, 1951 Dec., Baby Posters (Box 69)
  - #19, 1952 Jan., Sold-Colored Backgrounds, One Solid Color vs. Two or More (Box 69)
  - #20, 1952 Feb., Backgrounds: All-White vs. White Plus Colors (Box 69)
  - #21, 1952 Mar., Sex Appeal (Female) (Box 69)
  - #22, 1952 Apr., Single Package or Product vs. Multiple (Box 69)
  - #23, 1952 May, Beer Posters: Glass-Bottle Combinations (Box 69)
  - #24, 1952 June, Posters Advertising Two or More Products (Box 69)
  - #25, 1952 July, Women--Nude Shoulders (Box 69)
  - #26, 1952 Aug., Women Wearing Hats vs. Women Without Hats (Box 70)
  - #27, 1952 Sept., Illustrations of Women: Cropped vs. Uncropped; Wearing Hat/Not Wearing Hat (Box 70)
  - #28, 1952 Oct., Men Wearing Hats vs. Men Without Hats (Box 70)
  - #29, 1952 Nov., Illustrations of Men: Cropped vs. Uncropped; Wearing Hat/Not Wearing Hat (Box 70)
  - #30, 1952 Dec., Male Celebrities vs. Male Non-Celebrities (Box 70)
  - #31, 1953 Jan., Female Celebrities vs. Female Non-Celebrities (Box 70)
  - #32, 1953 Feb., Women in Large Hats vs. Women in Small Hats (Box 70)
    Includes data on unconventional hats.
  - #33, 1953 Mar., Auto Posters by Color of Car (Box 70)
  - #34, 1953 Apr., Success of Unusual Posters (Box 70)
  - #35, 1953 May, Full Figures Fully Clothed in Static or Near-Static Poses (Box 70)
  - #36, 1953 June, Full Figures Fully Clothed in Vertical Dynamic Poses (Box 70)
  - #37, 1953 July, Full Figures Fully Clothed, Vertical and Seated (Box 70)
  - #38, 1953 Aug., Full Figures Fully Clothed, Vertical-Kneeling (Box 70)
  - #39, 1953 Sept., Full Figures Fully Clothed, Horizontal-Reclining and Prone (Box 70)
  - #40, 1953 Oct., Full Figures Fully Clothed, Horizontal-Flying Through Air (Box 70)
  - #41, 1953 Nov., Full Figures Fully Clothed, Vertical Postures vs. Horizontal (Box 70)
  - Copy Clues Issue: Comprehensive Set 1: 1950 July-1951 July (Box 70)
  - Copy Clues Issue: Comprehensive Set 1: 1951 Aug.-1953 Aug. (Box 70)
  - Copy Clues Issue: Comprehensive Set 1: 1953 Aug.-1957 Apr. (Box 70)
  - Copy Clues Issue: Comprehensive Set 2: 1950 July-1952 Apr. (Box 70)
  - Copy Clues Issue: Comprehensive Set 2: 1952 May-1954 Oct. (Box 70)
  - Copy Clues Issue: Comprehensive Set 2: 1954 Nov.-1957 Apr. (Box 70)
- Other Surveys and Outdoor Advertising-Related Materials, 1954-1981
  This group of materials contains a variety of items that do not fit into other series. All materials relate to the business of outdoor advertising, and were likely used by Brennan in the course of his work. Surveys not handled by Brennan include two conducted in southern California. Other materials include written reports, resources related to other industry organizations such as OAAA and AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies). There are also additional documents produced by Brennan's companies that appear to go beyond the normal scope of business, such as special analyses on cigarette and canned soup preferences. Writings by others, usually on advertisement design, are also included, such as two papers written by Brennan's son, John P. Brennan.
  Materials are in alphabetical order by author, title, or topic. See also Legal Size Files for files in this series on the Highway Beautification Act hearings.
  - AAAA Research Guidelines--Demographic Breakdowns, 1963 (Box 71)
  - Brennan, John P., Outdoor Advertising Effectiveness, 1981 (Box 71)
  - Brennan, John P., A Pre-Testing Model for Outdoor Advertising Designs--Packaged Foods, 1981 Aug. (Box 71)
  - Brennan, John P., Strategic Review of the Outdoor Advertising Industry, 1978 Nov. 30. (Box 71)
  - An Econometric Model of Aided Male Brand Name Recall of Outdoor Gasoline Posters, OARI (Outdoor Advertising Research Institute), 1979 Nov. (Box 71)
  - Kolinsky, Muriel, Literature Search Relating to Space Position Value, 1954 June (Box 71)
  - Markets and Rates for Posters, OAAA, 1963-1964
    - Missouri--New Hampshire (Box 71)
    - New Mexico--North Carolina (Box 71)
    - North Dakota--Oregon (Box 71)
  - Nielsen Marketing Service Survey, 1966 Oct.-Nov., 3 folders (Box 71)
    (See also oversize folder at end of container list)
  - OAAA Officers and Committees, 1980 (Box 71)
  - Outdoor Advertising Bibliography, 1980 (Box 71)
  - Outdoor Advertising in the Los Angeles Metropolitan Area, Communicus, Inc., 1974 Oct. (Box 71)
  - PAS (Poster Appraisal Service) Analyses: Cigarette and Canned Soup Preferences, 1964 and undated (Box 71)
  - A Special Report Related to the Impact of 30-Sheet Posters, OARI/ PAS (Poster Appraisal Service), 1956 Jan. (Box 71)
  - Survey of Outdoor Advertising in Southern California, Haug Associates, 1974 July (Box 71)
- Legal Size Files, 1951-1965
  This group of materials contains items from previous series that required a larger container.
  - Methodology Files
    - Showing Size Adjustments, 1951, 1960 (Box 72)
  - Summary Data
    - Product Group Classification, 1959-1960 and undated (Box 72)
  - Other Surveys and Outdoor Advertising-Related Materials
    - State Hearings-- Highway Beautification Act, 1965
      - Nebraska--New Hampshire (Box 72)
      - New Jersey (Box 72)
      - New Mexico, New York, North Carolina (Box 72)
      - North Dakota--Wyoming (Box 72)
- Additions, 1947-1979 and undated; 1
  - General Files, 1948-1979 and undated; 1
    - General Media--Survey Objectives and Methods, 1961 (Box 73)
    - Loose photographs, negatives and slides, 1948-1950 and undated; 3 folders (Box 73)
    - Military recuitment poster surveys, 1955-1957 (Box 73)
    - Natural gas poster surveys, 1956-1965 (Box 73)
    - Outdoor Advertising Inc. (OAI)--Profile of Outdoor Advertising Readers, 1963 (Box 73)
    - Outdoor Advertising Research Institute (OARI)--An Econometric Model of Aided Male Brand Name Recall of Outdoor Gasoiline Posters, 1979 (Box 73)
    - Outdoor Advertising Research Institute (OARI)--Promotional newsletter, 1958 (Box 73)
    - Product index, survey forms, undated (Box 73)
    - Standard Outdoor Advertising--"Short copy" advertising series, undated (Box 73)
  - Surveys by City, 1947-1966; 2
    - Akron, 1963-1964 (Box 73)
    - Albuquerque, 1963 (Box 73)
    - Baltimore, 1955-1963 (Box 73)
    - Boston, 1954-1964 (Box 73)
    - Bridgeport, 1963 (Box 73)
    - Chicago, 1963-1965 (Box 73)
    - Cincinnati, 1948-1958; 6 folders (Box 73)
    - Cleveland, 1965 (Box 73)
    - Columbus, 1963 (Box 73)
    - Dallas, 1949-1964; 4 folders (Box 73)
    - Denver, 1963 (Box 73)
    - Des Moines, 1963 (Box 73)
    - Detroit, 1963-1964 (Box 73)
    - Fresno, 1948-1963 (Box 73)
    - Houston, 1954-1963; 4 folders (Box 73)
    - Houston, 1956-1966; 4 folders (Box 74)
    - Indianapolis, 1963 (Box 74)
    - Jackson, 1963-1964 (Box 74)
    - Jacksonville, 1964 (Box 74)
    - Los Angeles, 1949-1966; 8 folders (Box 74)
    - Lima, 1963 (Box 74)
    - Lubbock, 1963 (Box 74)
    - Market Four, 1963 (Box 74)
    - Memphis, 1963 (Box 74)
    - Miami, 1947-1963 (Box 74)
    - Minneapolis-St. Paul, 1963-1964 (Box 74)
    - Montgomery, 1963-1964 (Box 74)
    - New Haven, 1947-1958; 2 folders (Box 74)
    - New Haven, 1948-1958; 5 folders (Box 75)
    - New Orleans, 1963 (Box 75)
    - New York, 1965 (Box 76)
    - Norfolk, 1954 (Box 76)
    - Omaha, 1963 (Box 76)
    - Phoenix, 1963-1964 (Box 76)
    - Pittsburgh, 1963 (Box 76)
    - Portland, 1953-1955 (Box 76)
    - Pueblo, 1965 (Box 76)
    - Richmond, 1963 (Box 76)
    - Rochester, 1963 (Box 76)
    - San Diego, 1964 (Box 76)
    - San Francisco, 1960-1964; 3 folders (Box 76)
    - Seattle, 1963 (Box 76)
    - St. Louis, 1962-1963 (Box 76)
    - Tulsa, 1963 (Box 76)
- Oversize Folder, 1966
  - Other Surveys and Outdoor Advertising-Related Materials
    - Nielsen Marketing Service Survey, 1966 Oct.-Nov. (Box 72)
      Map with sample travel illustrations.